Benjamin Smith Barton Papers 1789-1815 Mss.B.B284d
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1783-1817 (Box 1-6)
  - Eliot, John, 1799 April 17-1805 Nov. 19; 3 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1799 April 17; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1801 May 17; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 November 19; ALS, 1p.
  - Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820, 1795 November 30; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Enkelem, G., 1788 October 03; 1 item
    - to the Secretary belonging to the Society of Arts and Sciences at Philadelphia, ALS, 4p.
  - Eustis, Dr., 1814, November 10; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
      Note about writing Eustis a letter.
  - Evans, David E., 1808 June 18; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
      illustrations
  - Everett, Charles, n.d.; 2p.
    - to Dr. John Willis, ALS, 2p.
  - Ewing, Samuel, 1807 September 26; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - F., J., 1808 December; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Fabricius, Johan Christian, 1745-1808, 1795 December 20; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Fatio, Mr., n.d.-1811 May 5; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton to Mr. Ramirez, 1811 May 05; AN, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ANS, 1p.
  - Fell, Jesse, 1798 January 03; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Fernagus, Jean Louis, 1813 November 13-n.d.; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 November 13; ALS, 1p.
      About the purchase of a natural history atlas
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ANS, 1p.
  - Ferrall, Miss, 1807 November 15; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 November 15; ANS, 1p.
      Regarding his account.
    - to unknown, n.d.; AN, 1p.
      About potatoes.
  - Ferville, James, 1812 January 26; 1 item
    A 21-page letter to "Jane" about her abominable behavior apparently written from a jail cell.
    - to "my former child", ALS, 21p.
  - Ffitt, Stubens, 1813 July 17; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
      Barely readable. Topic difficult to determine.
  - Field, Andrew, 1815 February 05; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Finley, Anthony, 1811 November 13; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Fisher, Charles F., 1812 February 27; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Barton Smith, ALS, 1p.
  - Fisher, John, 1809 May 07; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Fitzhugh, Alexander, 1813 October 30; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Floyd, John, 1812 March 02; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Foster, S .B., 1811 May 30; 1p.
    Concerning naturalist publications.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Foster, Strickland, 1812 February 29; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Fothergill, Anthony, 1732?-1813, 1804 September 12; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 8p.
      An interesting letter all about brewing various hop-related beverages.
  - Foushee, J. H., 1800 November 04; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Fox, Ann, 1809 April 29-n.d.; 1 item
    - Memo of amounts owed to him by Mr. Hopkins, 1809 April 29; AN, 1p.
    - to Mrs. Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
      Requesting that Dr. Barton send a French translation of a publication.
  - Fraquair, Adam, 1809 July 19; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Fraser, N., 1805 February 04; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, Fragment of ALS, 1p.
  - Freitos, Antonio Caetano de, 1804 July 07-1811 April 29; 7 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 July 07; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 March 18; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 September 3; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 January 13; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 March 26-27; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 April 29; ALS, 2p.
    - Memo from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; AN, 1p.
  - Frisbie, John H., 1803 November 04; 1 item
    - to David Hosack, ALS, 28p.
  - Fry, Mr., 1810 January 16; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849, 1810 March 14; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Garland, Samuel, 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
      Declining an invitation.
  - Geddes, James, 1808 March 14-n.d.; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 March 14; ALS, 1p.
      An illustrated description of a new crank.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; AL, 1p.
  - Genet, Citoyen, 1793 July 28; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
      A short greeting and request for a meeting with Barton.
  - Geyer, Andrew, 1805 August 31; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ADS, 1p.
      Extract from minutes of managers of almshouse regarding Dr. Petre.
  - Geyer, John, 1814 March 12; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
  - Geyer, Simon, 1811, July 08; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
  - Gibson, George, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Isaac Kagey, Ams, 1p.
      In Barton's handwriting.
  - Gibson, John, 1814 April 12; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Giguilliary, Charles, 1813 November 23; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Girardin, Louis, 1806 September 23-1808 July 7; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 September 28; ALS, 2p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 July 08; ALS, 1p.
  - Glover, Joseph, 1780-1840, 1806 October 20-1814 April 14; 7 items
    Mostly letters of introduction.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 October 20; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 July 23; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 July 3; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 October 26; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 October 21; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 October 10; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 April 14; ALS, 2p.
  - Good, John Mason, 1764-1827, 1810 February 11-1812 Jan. 12; 2 items
    - From Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 January 10; ALS, 1p.
      Discussion on the appropriate publication for a paper on potatoes.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; AN, 1p.
      About copy of letter.
  - Goodwin, Daniel, 1804 November 1; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Goodwin, William, 1813 March 31-1813 Oct.22; 2 items
    Concerning one of Barton's patients.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 March 31; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 October 22; ALS, 2p.
  - Gough, John Parker, 1811 July 30; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Granger, G., 1808 June 04; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Grant, Thomas, 1811 August 29; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Gratz, Simon, 1815 April 15; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Graustein, Jeannette Elizabeth, 1892-?, 1954 January 25-1955 Oct.; 2 items
    - to General Delafield, 1954 January 25; ALS, 1p.
      Regarding the Nuttall letters.
    - Copy of an article about Nuttall by Graustein, 1955 October; TMsCy, 5p.
  - Gray, H.M., 1807 April 08; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS
  - Gray, Thomas, 1805 April 02; 1 item
    - to Henry M. Gray, ALS, 3p.
  - Gray, Young A., 1813 November 1; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Grayson, William, 1808 August 25; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Green, Ashbel, 1762-1848, 1807 June 18-n.d.; 2 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 June 18; ALS, 1p.
    - to Alexander Wilson, ALS, 1p.
    - from Alexander Wilson, ALS, 1p.
  - Greenlee, S., 1809 March 19; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Greenway, James, 1790 February 19-1794 March 3; 6 items
    - Part of an abstract to be published., 1790 February 19; AMsS, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1791 October 17; ALS, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1792 September 14; ALS, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1793 January 21; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1793 January 31; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1794 March 3; ALS, 4p.
  - Gregg, Amos, 1803 December 23-1807 Oct. 16; 9 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1803 June 02-1806 August 2; Ams, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1803 December 23; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 July 08; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 September 06; ALS, 6p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 September 10; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 January 28; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 May 20; ALS, 2p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 July 01; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 August 13; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 August 04; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 October 10; ALS, 4p.
  - Griffitt, Robert E., 1805 December 06-n.d.; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Rush, 1805 December 06; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 2p.
      Griffitt seems to be defending himself to Dr. Barton.
  - Grimes, John, 1804 July 18-1814 March 18; 3 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 July 18; ALS, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 September 23; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 March 18; ALS, 3p.
  - Grosjean, John, 1814 March 05; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Guest, Henry, 1793 December 15-1795 Aug. 12; 2 items
    - to Robert Patterson, 1793 December 15; ALS, 2p.
    - to Robert Patterson, 1795 August 12; ALS, 2p.
  - Guille, Joseph F., 1804 October 28; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Hall, Elisha, 1740-1812, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; Ams, 1p.
      Attacks Cullen's theory.
  - Hall, Frederick, 1780-1843, 1807 June 16-1808 March 24; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 June 16; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 March 24; ALS, 3p.
  - Hamilton, Andrew, 1815 March 04-1815 March 6; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 March 04; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 March 06; ALS, 1p.
  - Hamilton, William, 1802 December 21-1813 Oct. 23; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
      About loaned books.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 October 23; ALS,
      Folder marked: "Letter missing from folder 9-19-1990"
  - Hanaby, James, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, Ams, 1p.
  - Harper, Francis, 1886-?, 1940 November 20-1942 Feb. 6; 8 items
    All 8 items are related to Bartram's natural history illustrations in Mrs. Delafield's possession. Francis Harper appears to be an employee of the Academy of Natural Sciences in Philadelphia.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1940 November 20; TLS, 2p.
      Regarding six additional Bartram's drawings.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1940 November 26; TLS, 1p.
      Regarding the new Bartram drawings of plants.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1940 December 06; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1941 December 06; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1941 December 19; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1941 December 20; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1942 January 1; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1942 February 06; TLS, 1p.
  - Harris, Levett, 1805 September 15-1810 July 13; 5 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 September 15; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 July 26; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 June 25; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 July 08; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 July 13; ALS, 1p.
  - Harris, Tucker, Jr., 1747-1821, 1801 November 25; 1 item
    - to George Logan, ALS, 2p.
  - Harrison, William, 1810 February 13; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Harvey, M., 1812 May 28; 1 item
    A great letter about an earthquake, meteor shower, a woman giving birth to a "black and white" child, and a billiard ball-sized stone which turned out to be fossilized dung.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Hawley, Henry C., 1809 March 31; 1 item
    - to the President of the Botanical Society, ALS, 2p.
  - Hayes, John, 1814 October 28; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Hayes, Nathan, 1809 May 07; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Hayward, George, 1791-1863, 1814 September 10; 1 item
    Describing London, Edinburgh, and Paris.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Hazzard, Thomas, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Heartt, D., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823, 1795 August 04-1798 March 10; 8 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1795 August 04; ALS, 3p.
    - to Bejamin Smith Barton, 1795 August 22; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1795 September 20; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1795 September 26; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1796 February 02; ALS, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1796 May 17; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1796 August 29; Xerox of ALS, 2p.
      About a "white negro."
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1798 March 10; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1798 April 09; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1800 April 12; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 March 04; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 April 26; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 January 27; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 September 11; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 March 29; ALS, 2p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; AMsS, 2p.
  - Hening, William H., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Herholdt, Johan Daniel, b.1764, 1808 March 27-n.d.; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
    - Subscription advertisement, n.d.; Broadside, 1p.
  - Herrick, W. W., 1937 August 29; 1 item
    Regarding a portrait of Benjamin Smith Barton.
    - to General John R. Delafield, ALS, 1p.
  - Heuvelly, K. W. van der, 1797 April 26-1798 Feb. 11; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1797 April 26; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1798 February 11; ALS, 2p.
  - Hewson, Thomas T., 1773-1848, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Heylin, J., 1814 November 07; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Higginson, S., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Hildreth, S. P., 1810 August 20-1810 Sept. 24; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 August 20; ALS, 2p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 September 24; ALS, 1p.
  - Hill, William, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Holmes, Abiel, 1763-1837, 1809 September 16; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Hoops, Adam, ?-1836?, 1811 June 13-1814 March 31; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 June 12; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 March 31; ALS, 1p.
  - Hopkins, ?, 1809 April 29; 1 item
    Folder says see: Fox, Ann to Mrs. Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.
  - Hosack, David, 1769-1835, 1815-n.d.; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815; ALS, 1p.
      Invitation for Barton to stay at Hosack's New York residence.
    - Classification of Diseases, n.d.; Broadside, 2p.
  - Hoskins, John, Jr., 1816 October 28; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Hubbard, John, 1807 August 27; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Hughes, Daniel, Jr., 1810 September; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Hughes, Robert, 1786 May 13; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Huling, William E., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
  - Hunt, Robert, 1798 July 26-179-; 1 item
    Regarding the expense of attending Princeton university.
    - Circular from Princeton, 179-; Broadside, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1798 July 26; ALS, 1p.
  - Hynes, Andrew, 1813 October 27-1814 Jan. 14; 3 items
    Describing a trip to Washington. Thanking Barton for taking care of his brother, Thomas, while he was in Philadelphia and also mentioning Thomas's recent ill health.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 October 27; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 November 08; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 January 14; ALS, 3p.
  - Inge, Richard, 1780-?, 1811 September 11; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Jackson, Henry, n.d.; 2 items
    - List of the measurement of Africans, Ams, 1p.
      Measurement of forearms compared with height.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
      Explanation of the measurement technique.
  - Jackson, Samuel, 1787-1872, 1809 January 07-1812 Sept. 19; 2 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 January 07th; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 September 19; ALS, 1p.
  - Jacobs, William Stephen, 1779-1843, 1811 July 27; 1 item
    Mentions stone hatchets, seeds, and the bearer of the letter, John DeBritton
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - James, Daniel, 1813 March 02; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - James, T. J., 1805 May 09; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - James, Thomas Chalkley, 1766-1835, 1815 November 14-n.d.; 1 item
    Expressing regrets at Barton's illness and his suspended activities at the University.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 November 14; ALS, 2p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS,
      a barely legible note about an universtiy election
  - Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826, 1801 January 1-1970 Aug. 17; 6 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1801 January 18; ALS, 4p.
      Asking for Jefferson's patronage for a friend.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 October 12; ALS, 1p.
      Asking Barton to assist his grandson, Thomas Jefferson Randolph, who was attending Barton's lectures.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 September 14; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 April 13; ALS, 1p.; Letter to Barton, promising to forward a request to the current President, and asking for news on Barton's new book and findings from the Lewis and Clark expeditions.
    - to Stephen Cathalan, 1815 March 06; ALS, 1p.
    - to Jean T. Williams from Julian P. Boyd, 1970 August 17; TLS, 1p.
      Boyd, the editor of "The Papers of Thomas Jefferson," informed Williams that the letter from Barton to Jefferson dated 18 Jan. 1801 was probably not sent.
  - Jenkins, J., 1804 September 23; 1 item
    - Extract of a letter from John Wyche to a Student of Medicine in Philadelphi, ANS, 1p.
  - John, Thomas H., 1806 February 07; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Johnson, Edward, 1767-1829, 1805 December 21-1807 Nov. 4; 3 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 18--; ALS, 3p.
    - to George A. Backster, 1805 December 21; ALS, 1p.
      Encourage correspondence between Backster and Johnson.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 November 04th; ALS, 3p.
  - Johnston, James Chew, 1787-1864, 1810 September 16; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Jones, Calvin, 1804 December 27; 1 item
    - to Dr. Lieb, ALS, 1p.
      Regarding a meeting of the Royal Medical Society of North Carolina. Folder indicates that Jones is the author. The letter, however, is much more ambiguous since it lists several names at the very end.
  - Jones, H., 1814 March 30; 1 item
    - to Rebecca Jones ("Mama"), ALS, 3p.
  - Jones, Mrs., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Josslyn, Charles, 1807 November 09; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Jourdan, John, 1806 August 12; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Jussieu, Antoine Laurent de, 1748-1836, 1809 August 05; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Keating, W., 1812 July 06; 1 item
    Regarding an answer to Francis King's letter.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
  - Keegan, Thomas, 1812 October; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Kimber & Conrad, 1814 August 08-1814 Aug. 9; 1 item
    Regarding Barton's books and discount.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton on reverse, 1814 August 09; ANS, 1p.
  - King, Francis, 1814 April 11; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 5p.
  - King, James, 1811 May 14; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
  - Kite, Thomas, 1814 January 24; 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
      Regarding the estate of Abel Dickenson.
  - Kiteley, James, 1799 August 21-1801 April 9; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1799 August 21; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1801 April 09; ALS, 1p.
  - Kollock, L., 1808 October 11; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Kops, Jan, 1765-1849, 1807 January 06; 2 items
    - Duplicate written in French, 1807 January 6; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 January 06; ALS, 3p.
  - Kramsh, Samuel, 1794 June 22; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Kreeger, F., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
      A note requesting that Barton sign a certificate.
  - Kuhn, Adam, 1741-1817, 1797 September 29; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - L., J., 1796 August 26-1797 April 27; 2 item
    - Subscription solicitation by Joseph Hawkins, 1796 August 26; Broadside, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1797 April 27; AMsS, 1p.
  - L., W., n.d.; 1 item
    The entire letter is a passage quoting Sir Isaac Newton used in a lecture on optics.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Lacepede, Bernard Germaine Etienne de Laville sur Illon Comte de, 1756-1825, 1802 October 31-1814 July 10; 3 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1802 October 31; ALS, 2p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 September 17; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 July 10; ALS, 2p.
  - Lane, Allen M., 1814 February 09; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Langley, W., 1814 February 07; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Langsdorff, George De, 1810 April -1813 Dec. 1; 3 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 April; ALS, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 August 12; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 December 1; ALS, 3p.
  - Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820, 1814 October 23; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Law Society of Philadelphia (Pa), 1810 April 30; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton signed by D. Waters, TMsCy, 1p.
      Requesting that Barton deliver a speech.
  - Leach, William Elford, 1790-1836, 1815 September 1; 1 item.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Leake, Richard, 1813 October 21; 1 item
    Regarding the extract from the Aurora.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Lechtenstein, Augustus Henri, n.d.; 1 item
    - Botanical notes, AMsS, 3p.
  - LeConte, John, 1784-1860, 1811 October 04-1812 Sept. 8; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
    - Le Conte's thoughts on Bartram written by Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 October 04; ANS, 1p.
  - Leigh, Egerton, 1815 February 11-1815 March 20; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 February 11; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1815 March 20; ALS, 1p1p.
  - Leon, Solomon de, 1792 December 31; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Leott, John B., 1812 July 11; 1 item
    - to William T. Leott, ALS, 2p.
  - Lettsom, John Coakley 1744-1815, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, AL, 4p.
      Fragment of a letter.
  - Lewis, C. W., 1809 July 14; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Lewis, W. B., 1797 November 04; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Lingelbach, William Ezra, 1871-?, 1948 October 12; 1 item
    Indicating interest in acquiring papers of Benjamin Smith Barton.
    - to John R. Delafield, TLS, 1p.
  - Linnaean Society of New England, 1815 January 27; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, TMsSCy, 3p.
  - Linnean Society of America, 1803; see oversized